# Weiyu (Nick) Chen

US Citizen • New York City • +1 (917) 815-2210 • chen.nick.dev@gmail.com • GitHub • Portfolio • LinkedIn

# **SUMMARY**

Software Engineer with experience in developing and testing interactive web applications with React, Python, and databases as well as building RESTful APIs. Proven skills in problem-solving, communication, and teamwork. I'm interested in working on highly impactful technical challenges to help the world be more open and connected.

# **SKILLS**

- Front-end: JavaScript, React, Next.js, TypeScript, jQuery, HTML, CSS, Tailwind, Bootstrap, StyledComponents
- Back-end: Python, Node.js, SQL, Express.js, Flask, Git, PostgreSQL, MongoDB, API
- Testing: Jasmine, Jest, React Testing Library, Pytest, Doctest, Unit Testing, SuperTest, E2E Testing
- Other: Mandarin, AWS, VSCODE, Git, Heroku, Firebase, Webpack, Docker, Data Structure, Algorithm

#### **PROJECTS**

#### **Admin Dashboard App**

A complete dashboard app using industry-standard packages that allow users to browse information and data

- Encourage the adoption of a front-end architecture that prioritizes user-centered design and supports React.js principles
- Incorporated React.js file and folder workflow, theme with Light and Dark Mode
- React, Material UI, Nivo Charts, Formik, Yup, FullCalendar, Data Grid, and Light & Dark Mode

#### **Social Media App**

A full-stack social media application built with MERN stack that allows users to create, like, delete and share ideas

- Established server using Node.js and Express; created schema data of each model to link the database with MongoDB
- Implemented JSON Web Token (JWT) based authentication for signup and login
- React, Express, Node, MongoDB, JWT Auth, Markdown

#### **Netflix Clone**

A full stack, frontend & API Netflix Clone that enables users to watch the live trailers available

- Promote implementing a responsive user-centered design front-end architecture to support React.js concepts
- Incorporated React.js workflow as a front and backend flex developer
- React, JavaScript, Node.js, Material-UI, HTML, CSS

# **PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE**

# **Software Engineer Fellow**

Full Stack Engineering, Springboard | New York, NY

May 2021 - May 2022

- Completed an 800-hour course covering critical aspects of front-end, back-end web development, and databases. Modules include learning resources, practice projects, and career-related coursework
- Highlighted skills learned: Web Development, JavaScript, DOM Manipulation, Event Driven Programming,
  Git/Terminal/Github, Modern JavaScript and Testing, AJAX, jQuery, ReactJS, Redux, SQL, PostgreSQL, Flask, Node.js, Express,
  Data Structures, and Algorithms

# **Store Development Manager**

Food Services Industry, Mudflow Tea Inc. | Brooklyn, NY

May 2018 - Present

- Formed a 500-customer base by delivering excellent service and developing social platforms
- Secured partnerships with UberEats, Grubhub, and Doordash and increased total revenue by 40% yearly
- Supervised and trained new employees, Coordinated operations, public relations, and events execution, decreasing preventable errors by 70%

# **EDUCATION**

**Software Engineering Certificate, Springboard Boot Camp** | New York, NY **Leetcode 100 Days Badge, AlgoExpert, Udemy, Harvard University CS50** 

May 2021 – May 2022 Jan 2020 - Present Aug 2012 – Aug 2014

Computer Science, University at Buffalo | Buffalo, NY